《非常小特务》
卡门 朱尼 睡觉了
Carmen,Juni,time for bed.
- 刷牙了吗？- 刷了
- Did you brush your teeth? - I already did.
- 朱尼 刷牙了吗？- 好啦 好啦
- Juni,don't forget to brush... - I am,I am.
好了
All right,all right.
好了 疹子
OK,warts. Uhh!
准备好对抗吧
Prepare to meet your maker.
学校都还好吗？
Everything OK at school?
不错啊 很好
Yeah. It's good. It's fine.
那好 关灯咯
OK. Well,lights out.
先讲故事
Bedtime story first.
想听什么故事？
What story do you want to hear?
间谍情深
"The Two Spies Who Fell In Love."
好久没说这个
I haven't told that one in a while.
你都比我熟了
You probably remember that better than I do.
- 要听故事吗 朱尼？- 我在听啊
- Want to hear a story,Juni? - I'm listening.
好
OK.
很久以前
Once upon a time...
有一个男人和女人
there was a man and a woman.
- 他们都是间谍 - 对
- And they were both spies. - Yes.
来自不同的国家
She from one country,he from another.
她要执行一项很重要的任务
She had a very important mission assigned to her.
- 任务就是"他" - 没错
- He was her mission. - Correct.
她的任务是带他"出去"
Her mission was to take him out.
约会？
On a date?
不是 带去做
No. Uh,take him...
喔 你是说
Oh,you mean...
我不该说这个
I shouldn't be telling you this.
- 说嘛 - 那是个
- Go on. Go on. - You have to understand...
很混淆 黑暗的时代
these were dark and confusing times.
国与国之间非常动乱
An enormous amount of turmoil between countries.
于是创造了新型战士
Out off ear a new kind of soldier was created...
一种聪明 勇敢的战士
brilliant,brave soldiers...
最强的武器就是他们脑袋
whose greatest weapons were their minds.
这些男人女人 被称作"间谍"
Those men and women were spies.
他们是伪装高手
They were masters of disguise.
远在一英里外就能嗅出危险
They could sense danger a mile away...
只要他们出手
and through their work...
战争不必开打就结束了
wars were ended before they even started.
间谍唯一怕的就是
The only things spies were truly afraid of...
别的间谍
were other spies...
敌国的间谍
enemy spies.
所以有时候 间谍的任务
So,sometimes,one spy's mission...
就是要让敌人消失
was to make the enemy disappear.
这个任务改变了她的一生
He was the assignment that changed her life...
要执行任务的那一刻
but when the moment finally came to carry out her mission...
她竟下不了手
she couldn't do it.
他完全出乎她意料
He was different than she expected.
确实他很有魅力 很聪明
Sure,he was charming and intelligent...
而且非常忠诚
but he was unexpectedly honorable...
她了解到
and it made her realize...
多年不带感情的工作
how years of working with detached emotion...
代价太大
had taken its toll.
于是他们保持联系
So they kept contact...
吃过几次饭 很谨慎的
through lunch dates... very discreet.
他们不同国
After all,they were on different sides...
不能被人看见
so they could never be seen together.
去同一地出任务
Dinner dates followed...
就一起晚餐
wherever their mutual travels took them.
终于坠入爱河
And they fell in love...
他们决定一起面对
and they decided that,together they would embark...
此生最艰难的任务
on the most dangerous mission of all time.
什么？
What?
他们要结婚
They decided to marry.
哇
Wow.
到结婚那天
Oh,yes. On her wedding day...
她觉得这比以往出生入死的任务
she felt like she would rather brave a thousand deadly missions...
还更需要勇气
than go through with what she was about to attempt.
为什么？
Why is that?
婚姻这任务很复杂
Well,marriage is a mission so complex...
只有很勇敢 带点疯狂的人才能胜任
that only the most courageous and slightly insane need apply.
为维持婚姻 维持家庭
There's such an amazing series of obstacles...
有一连串的障碍要面对
one has to navigate to keep a marriage together much less family
连她这样刚强
that it frightened even her...
经验老到的间谍都会害怕
a hardened and experienced secret agent.
但当她看见他
But when she saw him...
毫不质疑地站在那
standing there with no doubt whatsoever...
如此确定他的抉择
so assured of his decision...
如此渴望未来一切
so enamored with what they were about to do...
她牵起他的手
she took his hand...
看著他眼眸深处
looked deep into his eyes...
说了那句最危险
and said the two most dangerous...
最坚定的话
most trusting words you can say to anyone.
什么？
What?
她说"我愿意"
She said,"I do. "
好酷喔
Oh,that's so cool.
但麻烦来了
Yeah. Then the problems started.
有一组人
Now,there was always some faction...
一直想铲除他们
that wanted at least one of them gone.
原本单打独斗 无可匹敌
On their own,each agent was notorious...
现在出双入对 目标就明显
but together,they made tempting targets.
于是他们退休
So,they retired...
定下来
settled down...
生儿育女
had a few kids.
某方面来说 这是另一种挑战
In a way,they exchanged...
从间谍转业成父母
one life of adventure for another trading espionage for parenthood
执行最神奇 不得已的任务
a mysterious and compelling mission in its own right.
过得还不错 说完了
And they're better off. The end.
不是从此幸福？
No "happily ever after"?
还不错吧
I said they were better off.
故事很棒 但结局要改
Great story,Mom,but it needs a new ending.
要加点怪物
It needs monsters.
是吗？
Is that right?
我看看你的…
Do you want me to look at your...
我擦药了
I put the medicine on.
好 小南瓜 晚安
OK,munchkin. Good night.
今晚说什么故事？
What was the story tonight?
我们的
Mmm. Ours.
我常常都担心
How many nights,I wonder...
你会害孩子做恶梦
do you send the children off to bed with nightmares?
卡门要我说的
Carmen asked for the story.
那段日子过去了
That life is over now.
我们现在是顾问 不是间谍
We are consultants,not spies.
今天我去学校
So I went to their school today.
见了校长
Had that meeting with the principal.
卡门每个月旷课两次
Carmen's been skipping school twice a month.
- 为什么？- 不知道
- Why? - I don't know.
还有朱尼说的那些朋友
And those school friends Juni talks about having?
迪亚哥和雷那多
Yeah. Diego somebody and Renaldo?
根本不存在
No such beasts.
别的小孩排挤他
It turns out,the other kids pick on him.
他没朋友
He has no friends.
他满脑子幻想 很不好
It doesn't help that he has his head in the clouds...
整天画那些鬼画
making these weird drawings...
看那些怪怪儿童节目
and burying himself into that demented kids show.
他们有秘密 格瑞利
They're keeping secrets from us,Gregorio...
都怪我们
and I think it's our fault.
被我们的遗传的
They've gotten this from us.
我们必须保密
We have good reason to keep secrets.
万一说出我们是间谍
If we told them we were spies...
当我们不在 他们就提心吊胆
they'd have visions of danger every time we leave the house.
说到秘密
Speaking of secrets...
你在那边干嘛？
what are you working on over here?
没什么…不重要
Oh,nothing important.
只是…
It's just...
干嘛每天早上都要这样？
Why do we have to do this every morning?
学校已经有运动课了
We already have P.E. at school.
你想整天挂在那吗 胆小鬼？
You gonna hang there all day,scaredy cat?
叫你别往下看
Told you not to look down.
没办法 我快滑掉了
I can't help it. I'm slipping.
是你小肥手抓不住
It's your butterfingers that are slipping.
快点
Uhh ! Hurry up!
我要…
I can...uhh !
你从一千尺掉下 变肉饼了
You just fell a thousand feet. You're a pancake.
- 才不是  - 你就是
- Am not. - Are too.
爬都爬不起来 肉饼
Don't trip getting up,pancake.
小肥手
Butterfingers.
给我等著瞧
We'll see about that.
(状况:失踪)
唐纳根？
Donnagon?
对 他失踪了
Yeah. He's missing.
昨晚瞒著我的？
Is this what you were hiding last night?
不想让你担心
I didn't want to worry you.
"暗黑破坏秀"要开始了
We now return to...
朱尼 干嘛看这个？
Juni,why do you watch that show?
好看啊!干嘛？
Because it's cool. Why?
你老是看这节目
Because that's all you ever do.
买它的电玩 录影带
Play its video games and watch the tapes.
为什么？
Do you know why,son?
要记住 不管你做什么
So,always remember,whatever you do...
都要相信自己
believe in yourself.
梦想才会实现
Your dreams will come true...
你 和你 和你 都要记住
for you and you and you.
这是什么 自画像？
What's this,a self-portrait?
"What's this,a self-portrait?"
- 妈 他学我说话 - 妈 她学我说话
- Mom,he's mimicking me! - "Mom,he's mimicking me!"
卡门 别理他
Carmen,leave your brother alone.
朱尼 别学你姐说话
Juni,stop talking like your sister.
- 别闹 - 别闹
- Stop it. - "Stop it."
- 你看 这真可怕 - 跟他说说
- Look at this. It's hideous. - Well,talk to him.
还是一个怪脸
It's a Fooglie idea.
我自己设计的
I designed it myself.
今天我非常高兴
Today we're very excited,because today...
因为有新人要来
we have a new character!
他在我们城堡外窥伺
We found him snooping around the castle last night.
大家来欢迎唐纳麦
I want you all to meet Donnamight.
爸 这新玩具上市
Dad,when Floop makes a toy out of that one...
要买给我
I want it!
当心
Honey!
停车!停
对不起
I'm sorry! I'm sorry!
如果有人欺负你
Anybody gives you a hard time in there...
记住你是克兹家人
remember,you are a Cortez.
克兹家族有什么了不起？
What's so special about being a Cortez?
很了不起
Lots of things.
木乃伊耶
Hey,it's the mummy.
绷带蛮酷的 木乃伊
Nice-looking bandages,mummy.
别闹我
Just stop it,man.
跟你说话 就乖乖听
When I'm talking to you,you listen.
那玩具人不错 给我看那个玩具人
Nice dolls. Here,let me see the dolls.
乖乖玩 让他们知道谁是老大
Have a good day,son. Show them who's boss.
有什么事吗 老弟？
Can I help you with something,macho?
我问你有什么事 大哥？
I said,"Can I help you with something,chief?"
我想大慨没有
I didn't think so.
我爸差点要扁你爸
My dad was gonna beat up your dad.
别再瞒我事情 好吗？
No more secrets. Deal?
就快瞒不住了
Soon. Definitely soon.
我还得跟他睡一间
I even have to share a room with him...
因为他怕孤单
because he's so afraid of being alone.
照顾朱尼
"Watch out for Juni,Take care of Juni.
教导朱尼
"Show Juni right from wrong."
我只该对自己负责就好
I shouldn't be responsible for anybody but me.
说的对 卡门
You're so right,Carmen.
克兹家人有什么了不起？
What's so special about being a Cortez?
真希望能到你的世界 怪脸
I wish I could go away to your world,Floop.
你就能当我朋友
You'd be my friend.
感谢来
I thank you all...
参加今天的展示
for attending today's demonstration.
我们每年付庞大资金
Year after year we pay outrageous sums of money to several inventors
给几位发明家改进科技
to come up with our technologies.
暗黑破坏王是梦想家
Mr. Floop is one such visionary.
他的脑筋有点问题
However,his inventions are somewhat questionable...
需要在评估
and,therefore,need to be evaluated.
你答应给我一支军团
You promised us an army,Mr. Floop...
但花了十亿只得到这个
but our first billion dollars bought us only this...
变种的间谍
mutated secret agents.
变异和洗脑过程
The mutative process and brain wipe...
造成他们心智混乱
caused their minds to turn to mush.
除了在我节目上表演 几乎没什么用
I have found little use for them except as novelties on my...
第二名机器人…
well,my children's show,currently rated number two?
第二名
Number two.
这些手指人是什么玩意？
What the devil are these finger men?
他们叫"大姆哥"
Oh. They're called Thumb-thumbs.
很厉害的机器人
Very capable robots.
废物!真没用
All thumbs. Useless.
这个你会喜欢
Mr. Lisp,I think you'll enjoy this.
门后面将出现一个 非常强悍的东西
Through that door,an awesome power will emerge.
你必须瞬间解决他
You will have but a moment to disarm it.
要在10秒之内
In exactly ten seconds.
7…
Seven...
5…
Five...
3…
Three...
强尼？
Johnny?
- 你犹豫了 - 当然犹豫 他是我儿子
- You hesitated. - I had to. He's my son.
你确定？
Are you sure?
他是我设计的
Actually,I designed him.
我创造了他
I built him !
他叫…
His name is...
X-52495 二号
X-5-2-4-9-5,the second.
这就是你的伟大发明？
This is your big idea?
像我孩子的机器娃娃？
Robot kids that look like my children.
总统的女儿？
The president's daughter?
一模一样的复制品
An almost-exact replica.
有时要想出伟大计划
Sometimes in order to think big...
得"从小"做起
you have to think small.
运用物理电机塑像
Through physio-electrical imaging...
我能复制出任何人
I can make them look like anyone...
全球最厉害的间谍
yet the cunning and intelligence...
其智慧都装置在这些
of the world's greatest espionage agents...
源源不断的小人里 我叫他们"间谍小子"
all rolled into tiny packages I call "Spy Kids."
"间谍小子"以你广博的知识
Tell me,Spy Kids with your vast stores of knowledge...
告诉我 人类说谎时
what are four of the five physiological indications...
会有哪些生理反应？
that a human being is lying?
还没完全做好
They're not quite finished.
少一个最重要的零件
Missing one crucial element.
少什么？
Missing what?
他们的头脑
Their brains.
这堆废铁哪可能像真小孩
These buckets of bolts will never pass as children !
我们要赶进度
We have a schedule to keep,Floop...
机会是不等人的 要快
a window of opportunity that's closing fast!
两天后我会来接收军团
We will be back in two days to pick up our army...
否则就拿走一切
or we'll take whatever you do have,cut our losses...
免得再让你这蠢发明浪费钱
and lay your entire silly empire to waste!
我没时间了
No more time.
小鬼们送李先生去他的直升机
Escort Mr. Lisp back to his chopper,children.
- 很棒的发明 - 谢谢你 迷你安
- That was brilliant,sir. - Thank you,Minion.
我得想办法完成他们
Now all I have to do is make them work for real.
- 你去哪？- 出任务
- You're going where? - On assignment.
几位"欧斯"成员失踪？包括唐纳根
Several OSS agents are missing,including Donnagon.
没人要求赎金 就这样失踪
No ransom,no demands. They just disappeared.
你退休了九年 现在又答应接任务
After nine years,you are accepting an assignment?
- 为什么？- 因为戴福林
- Why? - In a word,Devlin.
他亲自打给你？
Devlin himself called?
对 要我出任务
He called,asked me to go in.
我跟你去
I'm going with you.
英格丽 你一直想再接任务
Ingrid,you're always looking to go on another mission...
但我们有孩子了
but we have children now.
不能两个都离开
We can't both leave.
- 我想去冒险 - 拯救全世界
- I want to go on an adventure. - I want to save the world.
还想啊？甜心 还玩不腻？
Again? Honey,it's old.
要不是他们失踪
If it wasn't for Donnagon and the other agents...
我都想回绝
I would be turning this mission down myself.
甜心 真的
I mean,clearly.
你要让我失望？
You're gonna turn me down?
我？
Me?
间谍宝贝…
Spy boy.
英格丽…
Ingrid,Ingrid...Ingrid.
孩子怎么办？
What...what about the children?
- 菲利克斯伯伯 - 菲利克斯伯伯
- Uncle Felix! - Uncle Felix!
小可爱 你们好
Hey,churros,how are you?
上次来你这么高
Last time I saw you,you were this big.
缩水啦？
You're shrinking. What's up?
帮我拿包包
Here,take this bag.
谢谢你赶来
Thanks for coming on short notice,guy.
一家人嘛 人家都这么说
That's what families are for. That's what I hear,anyway.
我认识你吗？
Do I know you?
- 好像又… - 回到从前？
- Feels,uh... - Like old times?
是啊
Yeah.
S414往圣西西里
S-4-1-4 to Santa Cecilia on assignment to Bond.
任务:寻找失踪欧斯干员
Missing OSS operatives.
英格丽和格瑞利干员已上路
Agents Ingrid and Gregorio Cortez en route.
真高兴又听见这名字
Well,it's good to hear those names again.
- 晚安 葛小姐 - 你好 格瑞利…
- Good evening,Ms. Gradenko. - Hello,Greg.
还有克兹太太
And Mrs. Cortez.
更新资讯
Updates.
立刻载入主机
They're being loaded into your central now.
区域扫描
Scan the area.
好了
All right.
打电话回家吧？
Why don't we call them?
他们快上学了
They'll be getting up for school soon.
不知道他们准备好了没
They should know what we're up to.
英格丽…
Ingrid.
你说的对
You're right.
快十年没出任务
Oh,our first time out in nearly a decade...
满脑都是孩子
and all we can do is think about the children.
欧斯护航员将在…
You should see OSS escort,Agent...
(信号干扰)
请重覆会合地点
Repeat the rendezvous point.
相信自己
Believe in yourself.
接收到电视讯号了
Picking up a...a TV satellite?
"格瑞利和英格丽"
And you,Gregorio and Ingrid Cortez.
你们有我要的东西
I believe you have something that I want.
我认识 他是暗黑破坏王 有人跟踪
No. I know who that is. That's... We've got a follower.
想得美 看我的
Not for long. Watch this.
那是什么？
What's that?
我们被吸进去了
They got us. They got...
卡门变成的"怪脸" 就是这样子
And this is what Carmen would look like as a Fooglie.
"警告" 天哪
Oh,my God.
消防演习吗？
Is this a fire drill?
孩子们 穿上这个 时间很紧急
Put these on quickly. We don't have any time to...
跟我来 跟我来 快
Follow me. Follow me. Come on !
快 跟我来
Come on ! Follow me!
很多事要说 但没时间解释
There's a lot for you to know and very little time to explain.
菲利克斯伯伯
Uncle Felix!
第一 我不是你们伯伯
The first of which is,I'm not your uncle.
你爸妈是超猛大间谍
Your parents are international spies.
但是他们九年没出任务了
Good ones,but they've been mostly inactive for the last nine years.
你说什么？
What are you talking about?
我负责保护你们
I was assigned to protect your family...
出事了
but something's gone wrong.
我带你们去"避难屋"
I have to take you to the safe house.
不可能 他们不够酷
My parents can't be spies. They're not cool enough.
这很酷
That's cool.
定位器显示
According to the coordinates...
他们被带往亚洲…
in my locating device,they're being taken to Asia...
或者南美
or South America.
进去 我就来
Go in there. I'll be right back.
万一你没来？
And if you're not?
按蓝色关门
Hit the blue button to seal the door...
绿色启动
and the green button to go.
这是开玩笑吗？
Is this a joke?
好酷!卡门 你看
Cool! Carmen,look!
卡门
Carmen !
你们自己去"避难屋"
You'll have to go to the safe house without me.
- 快去 - 菲利克斯 小心
- Go now! - Felix,look out!
- 吔 吔 - 去找"欧斯"的人
- Yeah ! Yeah ! - Find the OSS!
说第三脑还在 要找到
Tell them the Third Brain lives! You must find...
小心你后面 菲利克斯
Felix,behind you!
那什么玩意？
What are those things?
快打
Get them!
菲利克斯 快打
Felix! Get them!
按下蓝纽 绿纽
Press the blue and green buttons.
不能丢下菲利克斯
We can't leave Felix behind !
没办法
Oh,yes,we can.
蓝色关门 绿色启动
Blue to close,green to go. Quick!
- 有绿纽 - 先按蓝纽
- Here's the green button. - Blue button first!
朱尼 你什么都不会
Juni! You never do anything right!
先按蓝的关上门
Blue,then green ! You gotta seal the door!
找不到蓝的
I can't find the blue!
等等
Hang on !
那是什么玩意？
What are those things?
不知道 但快追来了
I don't know,but they're catching up!
- 油门在哪？- 别乱碰东西
- Where's the gas pedal? - No! Don't touch anything !
白痴 你换到手动了
You weirdo! You switched it to manual!
这东西怎么弄？
How do you work this thing?
它设定要去避难屋
It was programmed to take us to the safe house.
朱尼？
Juni?
朱尼 你在下面干嘛？
Juni,what are you doing down there?
救命啊
Help me!
等等 我来救你
Hang on ! I'm coming to get you !
自动驾驶
Autopilot re-engaged.
哇
Wow!
上学一定迟到了
We are definitely gonna be late for school.
别发抖
Stop shaking.
没办法
I can't.
你会起更多红疹子
Stop shaking,or you'll give yourself more warts.
别担心 我们没事
We're gonna be fine. Just be cool...
照我说的做
and do exactly as I say.
好吧
OK.
欢迎搭乘"超级甘比"
Welcome to the N.I.X. Super Guppy.
朱尼 别乱碰
Juni,don't touch anything.
朱尼
Juni!
目的地:避难屋
Destination...safe house.
两个半钟头
Estimated time for arrival... two hours,thirty minutes.
- 眼睛闭上 - 为什么？
- Juni,close your eyes. - Why?
叫你闭上 好
Just keep them shut,all right?
好 张开吧
OK,you can open your eyes now.
谢谢
Thanks.
我是怕你倒在我身上哭
I just don't want you crying all over me.
再也见不到他们了
We're never gonna see them again,are we?
点心准备好了
Refreshments ready.
要来一首催眠曲吗？
Would you care for a lullaby,sir?
冲掉便便
Now flushing your poop.
真危险
Very dangerous.
暗黑破坏王的怪脸们
Characters from Floop's TV show.
他们是犯人
They're prisoners.
迷你安 我们需要第三脑
We need the Brain,Minion.
时间不多了
We're running out of time.
放心 先生 英格丽和格瑞利
Don't worry,sir. Ingrid and Gregorio Cortez...
是我所认识毫无弱点的间谍
are the only agents I know of that never had a weakness...
但现在不同了
but times change.
他们有了小孩
Now they have two.
你锁上了没？
Did you lock it?
锁了
Yep.
这就是"避难屋"？
That's the safe house?
我看蛮像公厕
Looks more like an outhouse.
你叫什么？
Your name?
卡门·克兹
Carmen Cortez.
请说全名
Your full name,please.
我不用全名 太长了
I don't use my full name. It's too long.
请说全名
Your full name,please.
卡门·伊丽莎白·安妮塔科斯塔·克兹
Carmen Elizabeth Juanita Costa-Brava Cortez.
我的名字是密码
My name's a pass-code?
这地方太奇妙了
This place is amazing.
空的
Empty.
没东西吃怎么能叫"避难屋"
How safe is a safe house if there's nothing to eat?
喷射背包
"Machete's Buddy Pack"?
急用现金？
Emergency cash?
各国都有
From every country.
全都拿了吧
I think I'd better take all of that.
吃吃看
Check it out.
说 谢谢卡门
Thank you,Carmen !
我们会再见面的 他们说过
We'll see them again. Just like they said.
这次要相信他们的话吗？
So this time we're supposed to believe them.
不用担心这些小家伙
Let's stop worrying about the children.
他们还穿着尿布
They still wear diapers.
只有一个晚上包
Only one is in diapers and only at night.
别大惊小怪
It's not that unusual,OK?
所以我不愿意出任务
This is why I never wanted to go on another mission.
你怪我？
Are you blaming me for this?
刚才你还很高兴
An hour ago you seemed happy to be back in the game.
刚才我还不是俘虏
An hour ago I was not a prisoner of war.
我们只是有点生疏
OK,we're a little rusty,that's all.
只有这样能找出主使者
This is one way to find out who's behind all this.
要好好运用压力
If I can just get the pressure right.
好在还没忘
She's still got it.
你怎么做的？
How did you do that?
我怎么办？
Hey,hey,hey,what about me?
以前我们很远就嗅出危险
Remember when we could sense danger a mile away?
- 美好往事 - 对
- Those were the days. - Yeah.
对
No.
甜心
Aah ! Sweetheart!
了不起
Clever.
好 快走
OK,OK,come on,come on.
- 好 - 好
- All right. - Yeah,yeah,fine.
真了不起
Very clever.
虚拟实境房
Virtual room.
我们走
Let's go.
这是哪？
Where are we?
想像力丰富 值得加分
You gotta give him points for imagination.
你们花了15分钟才逃脱
Fifteen minutes to escape.
以两位的名声我以为会有
With your reputations I was expecting something...
更好的表现
a little more impressive.
终于可以吃饭了
Finally,we can eat!
你就是暗黑破坏王
So,you are Floop.
你看我的节目？
Mmhh ! You watch my show!
我儿子看
No,my son does.
是吗？太棒了
He does? Wonderful!
卡门和朱尼
Carmen and Juni.
你女儿不看？
But not your daughter...
她叫卡门对吧？
Carmen,isn't it?
儿子叫朱尼
And Juni? Heh heh !
他们很快就会来了
Your children will be joining us soon.
小心点
Careful!
我弹弹手指
I snap my fingers...
大姆哥就会来弹你
and my fingers snap you.
你把欧斯干员藏哪？
Where are the OSS agents you've taken?
12年前
Twelve years ago...
欧斯有个研究小组
they were part of a research team for the OSS...
想创造一个综合智慧库
attempting to create a synthetic intelligence...
间谍知识大全的产物
a compendium of spy knowledge,if you will.
结果毁弃了
Research since destroyed.
欧斯毁弃这个研究
If the OSS destroyed its research...
一定有它的理由
it was for a reason.
大家都有理由
We all have our reasons,hmm?
这小组中有个人
There was someone else on that research team,hmm?
可以再造那个产物
Someone else who could rebuild it.
对吧 克兹先生？
Isn't that right,Mr. Corteth?
菲利克斯
Felix.
他会成为假期
I think he's gonna be a best-seller.
最抢手的玩具
And just in time for the holiday rush.
我绝不帮你做任何东西
I will never,ever build anything for you.
谢谢你加入
Thank you for joining us.
"完全间谍手册"
"How To Be A Spy. "
作者不详
Author unknown.
一个好间谍要…
"A good spy uses..."
测试 1 2
Testing ! One,two...
你太靠近了
Ow! Gosh ! You're too close!
好间谍要懂得用脑
"A good spy uses his head." Got that?
书上第一条
It's the first one in the book.
好恶
Ew,gross!
- 你看到什么？- 你
- What do you see? - You.
不好笑 眼睛靠近一点
Very funny. Focus your eyes closer...
在镜片有资料
on the glasses themselves.
哇 是地图和资讯
Whoa ! Maps and readouts.
是电脑荧幕
That's the computer screen.
像资料库
It's a database of some kind.
妈说的那故事
The wedding from the story.
是他们自己的
It was theirs.
她应该早说
They should've told us about this stuff.
你还不是骗说
Yeah? What about Diego and Renaldo...
你有一堆朋友
and all your make-believe friends?
你敢说吗？
Should Mom and Dad know about that?
你也跷课
What about all the days you skip school?
- 要我跟他们说吗？- 那是我的事
- Want them to know about that? - That's my business.
有钥匙吗？
Uh,Carmen?
我没钥匙 去找东西撬开
I don't have a key. Go knock it against something.
"好间谍什么都不怕"
"A good spy has no fear."
朱尼 你当不了好间谍
Sorry,Juni. Guess you can't be a spy.
好间谍会从敌人角度…
"A good spy puts himself..." herself...
思考问题
"in the mind-set of the opponent."
思考
Mind-set.
我们就这样做
That's exactly what we'll do.
只有靠我们了 你行吗？
I think it's up to us. You with me?
- 行什么？- 去找欧斯干员
- With you what? - Find the OSS like Felix said.
- 好吧 - 那我们走
- OK. - Then let's go.
我姓葛 是你父母同事
Hi! I'm Ms. Gradenko. We work for your parents.
我们？
"We?"
我知道你们很怀疑
I can understand if you don't trust me...
上次见面 你还是婴儿
You were a baby when we first met.
记得我了吗？
Remember me now?
抱歉 看 我有钥匙
Sorry. I have a key. You see?
我们是来保护你们
We're all on the same side. We're here to protect you.
我妈也有这手镯
My mom has a bracelet like that.
欧斯干员标志 我们都有
OSS standard issue. We all have one.
欧斯？你是他们同事？
OSS? You work with my parents?
对 仔细听好
Yes. Now,please listen closely.
张开耳朵听好
Open your ears.
你爸今天早上发给我们一个讯号
You father was able to send one last communique this morning...
就在他失踪前
before he disappeared.
有五个字
It consisted of five letters.
暗黑破坏王
F-I-O-O-P!
你错了
But you're wrong.
伟大的破坏王不会那样
Fabulous Floop would never do that.
相信我 他没那么伟大
Oh,trust me. He's not that fabulous.
而且 认识他们吗？
In fact,recognize these?
他的怪脸们
Floop's Fooglies.
我有他们玩具
I've got toy versions.
被转换前 他们是这样
This is what they looked like before he mutated them.
他们把间谍变成怪物？
You mean these mutants are captured secret agents?
- 那人是天才 - 我说过破坏王很厉害
- We're dealing with a genius. - Told you Floop was a freak.
那些怪脸唱的
And that cute,little tuneless song...
可爱的歌 倒回去听
the characters sing? Play it backwards...
破坏王疯了 快来救我们
We're trapped! Floop is a madman!
救命 救命
Help us! Save us!
破坏王疯了 快来救我们
Floop is a madman! Help us! Save us!
他们在求救
A cry for help.
爸妈也会变那样
Will Floop do that to Mom and Dad?
绝对会
Definitely.
除非得到你爸研究的一个东西
Unless he gets something your father helped develop.
你记不记得他提过一个
If there's anything you can possibly remember...
- 第三脑？- 什么？
- The Third Brain lives. - What?
菲利克斯叫我告诉欧斯一件事
Felix gave us a message to deliver to the OSS...
你就来了
and here you are.
对 我来了 什么事？
Here I am. What's the message?
第三脑还在
The Third Brain lives.
卡门
Ohh ! Carmen...
我宣布你正式成为 欧斯女间谍一员
you have just joined the ranks of women spies in the OSS.
太棒了
Brilliant.
- 臭女生 - 现在
- Girls. - Now.
第三脑在哪里呢？
Where does the Third Brain live exactly?
菲利克斯有告诉你吗？
Did Felix tell you that?
好像他没说
I don't think he said.
他没说？
He didn't say?
你确定？
Are you sure?
搜!
Search the place.
不在他家一定在这
It wasn't at the house,so it must be here.
你去过我家？
You were at our house?
糟了
Oh,no!
我的天
Oh,my God.
它真的存在
It exists.
暗黑破坏王就是要这个？
That's what Floop wants?
它真美
It's so beautiful!
她是破坏王手下
Carmen ! She's working for Floop!
穿上它飞到暗黑城堡
Fly this to Floop's castle immediately.
- 好的 妈妈 - 别动
- Yes,ma'am. - Don't move!
你根本不会用
You don't even know what those things are.
我知道它很重
I know they've heavy.
这装置要花一百万
Hey,they cost millions of dollars!
有这东西
That brain's the only thing...
爸妈就不会有事
keeping Mom and Dad from being zapped !
拦住她
Stop her!
叫大姆哥进来
Send in the thumbs.
等等我
Wait for me!
这玩意怎么弄？
Unh ! How do you work this thing?!
把她抓回来
Bring her back!
不想见爸妈吗？
Ah,ah,ah ! Don't you want to see your parents...
小捣蛋
you little brat?
- 呃 - 哦 抱歉
- Unh ! - Whoops! Sorry!
别抓我
Get back!
你们怎么搞的？孩子都抓不到
What's wrong with you? They're just children.
头发完蛋了
Bad hair day.
哦哦 起飞
Uh-oh. Going up!
干嘛？
What?
你去哪了？
Where did you go?
就在他后面 你呢？
I'm right behind him ! Where are you?
我很惨
I'm toast.
第三脑还我
Give me back that brain !
离我远点 大坏蛋
Get away from me! Tough guy,huh?
再见
See ya !
姐姐
Oh,my sister!
喔 老弟
Oh,brother!
我撑不住了
I can't hold on much longer!
抓紧 笨小孩
Get a grip,you big baby!
- 我往下滑 - 撑住 小肥手
- I'm slipping ! - Hang on,butterfingers!
我快不行了
I'm not gonna make it!
就快到了
We're almost there!
- 别把我丢下 - 我不会丢下你
- Don't drop me! - I'm not gonna drop you !
没有我你就完了
What would you do without me?
这是残酷的世界
It's a cruel,cruel world
小朋友
All you little boys and girls
有些坏蛋想吃掉你们
And some mean nasty people.Want to have you for their supper
跟我来 你们就会自由
But if you follow me you can all be free
自由 像鸟一样自由
Free,you can all be free
只要守着电视
As a bird on a big TV
只要你有梦 有梦
If you dream,if you dream
If you dream my dream
这是一个残酷的世界充满了讨厌的男生和女生
It's a cruel,cruel world full of nasty boys and girls
充满自私 意思是 讨厌的人
Full of selfish,mean,nasty people
讨厌 讨厌 讨厌 讨厌
Nasty,nasty,nasty,nasty
有个方法能让自己快乐
But there's a way you can make your day
你可以笑 可以来找我玩
You can laugh,you can smile,you can come and stay awhile
跟我一起玩 一起做梦
You can dream my dream,you can have it all with me
你我一起作梦
You can dream my dream,you can dream my dream
You can dream my dream
停
Cut!
把他们关起来
Lock them up!
还需要什么 迷你安？
What does it need,Minion?
- 我不… - 我的节目需要别的东西
- I don't... - My show! It needs something !
才能变成最棒的
That thing that will take it to number one.
我感觉得到
I can feel it...
但想不出来
but I can think straight enough to figure it out.
你花太多时间想节目
Floop,you're spending too much time on this program.
应该多想想大计划
You should be more concerned with our grand diabolical plan.
- 企业化？- 机器娃娃军团
- Syndication? - The army of robot children.
这机器人让我绞尽脑汁
This hardware gets in the way of my creative abilities.
你没抓到孩子
You lost the children.
他们逃了
Not only did they escape...
还带走"第三脑"
they took the Third Brain with them.
真的存在？
It exists?
真的 格瑞利骗我们
Completely. Cortez lied to us.
派最棒的大姆哥去
Send our best Thumbs.
要抓犯人就派犯人去抓
Sir,if you want to catch a criminal you send a criminal.
要抓间谍就派…
If you want to snare a spy...
快点说
Please speak English,Minion !
这灯光热死我了
I've been baking under those studio lights.
- 要抓小孩 - 嗯哼
- If you want to find a child... - Mm-hmm?
就该派小孩去
Send a child.
很聪明 迷你安
That is brilliant,Minion.
谢谢 先生
Thank you sir.
(圣狄博)
什么定位器
Some locating device.
座标在指什么
I can't even figure out where the coordinates point to.
谁做的？
Who makes this?
马雀公司
"Machete Products."
(马雀和红贝)
你在干吗？
What are you doing?!
在找爸妈全靠它
That's our bargaining chip on getting Mom and Dad back.
破坏王要的东西
This is what Floop wants.
爸妈一定希望毁掉
I think Mom and Dad would want this destroyed.
你怎么知道他们想要什么？
How do you know what they want?
连他们是间谍我们都不知道
Until this morning,you didn't even know who they were.
先把第三脑留著
We keep the brain.For now.
干嘛还带著它？
Why are you still wearing that?
搞不好是追踪器 他们可能追踪我们
That could be a tracer. They could be tracking us.
少用你的手指指我
Don't start pointing fingers at me.
我可没干蠢事 蠢蛋
I didn't do anything stupid,stupid.
别叫我蠢蛋
You better stop calling me names.
不然呢？
Or what?
不然我也叫你蠢蛋
Or I'm gonna call you names.
座标在右边
The booger was right.
真讨厌
I hate that!
不是叫你别缠我？
Thought I ditched you.
你穿这是什么衣服？
Why are you dressed like a geek?
我不是你姐了 走开
We're no longer relatives. Go away.
才说你蠢 你就更蠢
You're just getting stupider by the minute.
放开我
Get away from me.
放我下来
Hey! Put me down !
我早就想扁他
Always wanted to do this.
你很厉害喔
Ohh ! Tough guy,huh?
朱尼
Juni!
放我下来
Put me down !
把第三脑毁掉
Destroy the brain !
摧毁它
Destroy it!
第三脑被抢了？
They took the brain?
对 我拿了她项炼
Yeah,but I took her necklace.
- 她没注意 - 他们不聪明
- She didn't even notice. - They weren't very smart.
连话都不会说
Yours couldn't even speak.
"间谍小子限量版"
"Limited edition. Spy Kid.
"500之1"
"One of five hundred..."
破坏王做了几百个
Floop could have hundreds of these flying around.
第三脑能让他们变聪明
The Third Brain makes them smart.
就成了一支军团
They're building an army.
我们要救爸妈
We've got to save Mom and Dad.
只有他们能阻止机器人
Only they can stop the robots.
那谁来救我们？
But who's gonna help us?
我们完成了
We had it working.
综合智慧仪非常聪明
A synthetic intelligence as smart as any spy.
把那脑子锁紧吧？
Why don't you go ahead and tighten that brain up?
第三脑系统
The Third Brain System.
欧斯长官知道 若敌方取得这个技术
The OSS Director realized it was too dangerous...
会造成极大危险
if the wrong forces found the technology.
我们奉命摧毁它
We were ordered to destroy it.
已毁掉了 干嘛还瞒著我？
Why keep that a secret from me?
为了保护我们？
To protect us from something you destroyed?
还是你没毁掉？
Or something you didn't.
这么多秘密 瞒著你 瞒著孩子
All these secrets from me,from the children.
不能再这样
It has to stop.
对不起
I'm sorry.
他要第三脑
He wants the Brain.
如果要救孩子 全世界就会危险
If we save our children,we risk the world.
那会成了什么世界？
So what in the world do we do?
谢谢你开这么远
Thanks for taking us this far,but...
我只有这些钱
this is all we got.
来这里干嘛？
What are we doing here?
爸的代号一定是"红贝"
Dad's code name must be Hombre.
那这个就是"马雀"
So,this must be Machete.
我们要找爸的伴郎帮忙？
We're getting help from Dad's best man?
你在干嘛？
What are you working on?
做世上最小的摄影机
World's smallest camera.
看不见啊
I don't see it.
它看见你了
Ah,but it sees you.
你卖反间谍物品吗？
You sell counterintelligence stuff here?
- 找你爸妈去 - 不行
- Come back with your parents. - We can't.
我们需要最快的飞机去这里
We need something fast that can get us here.
你是谁？
Who are you?
卡门·伊丽莎白·安妮塔科斯塔·克兹
Carmen Elizabeth Juanita Costa-Brava Cortez.
格瑞利是我爸爸
Gregorio Cortez is our father.
你去了他的婚礼
You were at his wedding.
转过身去 离开我的店
You will turn around. You will leave my shop.
我不想再听到我弟名字
Because I never want to hear my brother's name again.
你是我们伯伯
You're our uncle?
真的伯伯吗？之前有个是假的
Our real uncle? 'Cause we already got a fake uncle.
格瑞利是我最小的弟弟
Gregorio Cortez is my younger brother.
总统的女儿
President's daughter.
总统的儿子
President's son.
很好
Oh,good.
首相的儿子
Prime Minister's son.
将军的女儿
General's daughter.
全按照计划 都在这了
They're all here as planned.
我要回去弄我的节目
I have to get back to my show now.
你该先解决眼前的任务
You must focus on the task at hand.
李先生快来接收军团了
We have to prepare the army before Mr. Lisp arrives.
我不想弄这个了 迷你安
I don't believe in this anymore,Minion.
我本来就不想
I don't think I ever did.
请解释
Explain.
变种间谍 机器人不是我的点子
The mutated agents,the robot kids.
是你的
Those aren't my ideas. They're yours.
所以呢？
So what?
所以我完成不了
I think that's why they're not working.
是还没完成
Not yet they're not.
但现在我有第三脑了
But,you see...I now have the Third Brain.
我也不需要你了
I don't need you anymore.
迷你安？
Minion?
你现在要开始叫我迷先生
I assure you,it's Mr. Minion now.
你已经被利用完毕
And you,Floop,have served your purpose.
间谍小子
Children...
把他关到"虚拟实境房"
lock him in the...virtual room.
你是间谍吧？
You're a secret agent,aren't you?
你那里听来的？
What makes you say that?
资料库显示你居无定所
According to the database,you're always traveling...
没人知道你的职业
and no one knows what you do for a living.
大家的伯伯都这样
I think we all have uncles like that.
又一个马雀的精品
"Another fine Machete product."
你制造全球最棒的间谍用品
You make the best spy inventions in the world.
没错
That's correct.
但好人坏人你都卖
But you sell them to both sides,good and bad.
所以爸爸不再跟你来往
That's why Dad hasn't spoken of you in all these years.
你也卖东西给暗黑破坏王吗？
Ever sell stuff to Floop?
问这干嘛？
Why?
我爸妈…
Our Mom and Dad...
你弟弟 被他抓了
your brother... are his prisoners...
如果不快想办法
and if we don't do something to help...
爸妈就完了
something really bad's gonna happen to them.
我不懂你为什么不救他
I don't see why you won't help him !
我干嘛像褓母一样照顾他一辈子
You think I want to baby-sit my brother the rest of my life?
小心格瑞利 照顾格瑞利
"Watch out for Gregorio. Take care of Gregorio.
要教格瑞利
"Make sure Gregorio knows right from wrong."
马雀只要对自己负责就好
Machete's not responsible for nobody but Machete.
一家人不该这样
But that's not what family is.
我们只是兄弟 圣经里兄弟
We're just brothers. Cain and Abel were brothers.
还自相残杀呢
Look how they ended up.
能最快让你们到暗黑城堡的
Now,the only thing that will get you to Floop's castle fast enough
只有这个东西
is this.
好小
It's tiny.
这只设计给一个人坐的 很快
It's built for one passenger,but it's fast.
你要去吗？
Will you go?
不
No.
- 为你弟弟？- 不去
- For your brother? - No!
为我们呢？你的侄儿侄女？
Then how about for us... your niece and nephew?
不
No.
- 那么… - 不 不去 一百万次不去
- How about if... - No! No! A million times no!
把猪肠递过来
Pass the pig intestines.
我不吃那个了
I'm not eating that now. Nope.
- 我能不能… - 不
- Can I have a... - No!
要一杯水
Glass of water?
谢谢留宿
Thank you for letting us stay here...
虽然我很担心爸妈
while we ponder our parents' terrible fate.
若不姓克兹 我才不留你们
If you weren't a Cortez,I wouldn't be doing this much.
亲情还是比金钱重要
So family does mean more to you than money.
不
No.
我爸很想你喔
Dad misses you,too.
好了吗？
Ready?
走吧
Let's go.
就是这个
Now we're talkin'.
你在干嘛？
What are you doing?
找去暗黑城堡的地图
Getting the map to Floop's castle.
那是反射动作
Shh. It's just a reflex.
看 他还在睡
Look. He's still asleep.
别叫大人去做孩子的事
Never send an adult to do a kid's job.
帅啊
Oh,yeah.
要我帮什么忙？
What can I do to help?
记得屋顶上的飞机吗？
Remember that spy plane up on the roof?
记得
Yeah.
看操作手册
Start reading.
做功课
Oh. Homework.
不
No!
快 他来了
Hurry up! He's coming ! He's coming !
再见 马雀大伯
Good-bye,Uncle Machete!
谢谢借我们飞机
Thanks for the plane!
好了 这就是新计划
OK,so here's the new plan.
我们去城堡救出爸妈
We get to the castle,rescue Mom and Dad...
阻止破坏王
then somehow stop Floop...
给机器人装脑子
from using the brain on the robots...
以免他们控制世界
before they're sent out to dominate the world.
- 我们行吗？- 会有多难？
- Think we can do that? - How hard could it be?
我啥都没做
I didn't do anything.
好 速度 没问题 高度 没问题
OK. Airspeed...fine. Altitude...fine.
自动驾驶
Autopilot...failing?
坏了 又一个马雀精品
Oh,great. Another fine Machete product.
来 我们要手动操控
Take control. We have to go to manual.
快
Now!
手册要全部看完
You were supposed to read all the instructions!
你少看一章 猪头
You skipped a chapter,meathead.
别叫我猪头
Better stop calling me names.
拉上去 白痴
Pull up,booger breath !
再那样骂我 我也要骂你
Stop it or I'll call you names.
看你能骂出什么 猪猡
Go ahead. You got nothin' on me,warthog.
你以为我不会"包尿布的"
Try me...diaper lady.
你现在最好有包著尿布
Aha. Hope you're wearing one now.
- 你怎么知道 - 早就知道了
- How long have you known? - Since forever.
妈叫我发誓不准说
Mom made me swear not to mention it.
我们扯平了
So now we're even !
看你干的好事
Oh,now you've done it!
我就知道会这样
I knew this was gonna happen !
再不想办法就撞机了
We're gonna crash if you don't do something !
你故意的 自杀狂
You did that on purpose,you kamikaze!
这样就平衡了
But now it's balanced!
降落装置
Landing gear.
不能降落 我们要撞机了
No landing gear. We're gonna crash !
不 我们跳机
Nope. We're gonna drop.
潜水装准备好
Get your regulator ready.
系统检测 你听得见吗？
Com systems check. Can you hear me?
可以
Yeah.
去那个山洞看看
Let's try that cave over there.
应该是这
This must be in.
你开玩笑吧
You are kiding me.
这个洞里都是鲨鱼
It's a cave of sleeping sharks.
鲨鱼又不睡床上
Sharks don't sleep on a bed.
我以前做过一个科学项目
I did a science project,
当水里的含盐量合适的话 鲨鱼就会聚在一起睡觉
Its depth the water salinization is just right,they gather to sleep.
守着这条路
And garding the way.
那边好像有个门
It looks like the door over there.
- 哇 太棒了 - 别碰它
- Whoa cool - don't touch it.
也是人吗？
Isn't the man either?
不 你不是一个人 你可能会认为这是一个超大的
No,you're not a man yet,you might think it's a oversized.
别玩了 走
Stop,going you up.
嗨 可爱的小鲨鱼
Hey,little sleeping shark.
傻瓜 它在睡呢
It sleeps,silly.
我知道
I knew that.
- 快点 - 嗨 可爱的小睡鲨
- Come on. - Cweet dream sharks.
有监控摄像头 我要去毁了它 你在这里等我
A surveilance camera. I'm gonna destruct it,you wait here.
- 别把我丢下 - 在这里等
- Don't leave me.- Wait here.
茄子
Say cheese
真希望附近能有个餐馆
I hope there's a restaurant around here.
我在摄像头前面
I take a picture of the door.
拍了一张门的照片
In place in front of the surveilance camera,
这样他们看不到我们进去
So they can't see us go inside
我真的要小便了 实在憋不住了
I gotta go pee,and I cann't hold it.
别 这样会改变海水的含盐量 把所有鲨鱼吵醒
Don't pee,you will change the water salinization and wake up all the sharks.
我实在忍不住了 全是…另外一个
I cann't help it.All this...another
我知道有个摄像头对着我 我有什么办法？
I know,another camera planting straight at me,what'd I do?
你怎么没看监控呢？
Why aren't you watching the monitors?
去叫更多的卫兵来
Get the more securities of here.
我要憋不住了
Oh.I can't hold it anymore.
我在破解密码 就快好了
I'm breaking the code,almost there
等等 继续破解
Wait a second Juni,keep coding it
哦 卡门
Oh...Carmen
迷你安 我就要弄好了
Minion,almost there.
卡门 我们最好离开这里 不要解码了
Carmen. we would go better,brother,no about the oversizde copies.
再见 睡鲨们
Goodbye the sleeps... all the sharks
- 情况有变化了 - 门开了 卡门
- Chang something...- the door is opened,Carmen.
- 我来了 - 那你最好再快点
- I'm coming. - you gotta faster.
我再也不能尿尿了
I'll never pee again.
大拇指
A Thumb-thumb.
真的有…
A real live...
你怎么弄的？
What did you do to him?
马雀的电击泡泡糖
Machete's electroshock gumballs.
上面写持久型 但我不相信
It says long lasting. But I don't trust wrappers.
快点
Come on.
过来 快
Over here. Juni,come on.
你干嘛？
What are you doing?
全球最小的摄影机
World's smallest cameras.
我放在每个主要通道
I just placed them all over the main hallways.
- 聪明 - 谢谢
- Sweet. - Thanks.
大姆哥和怪脸们 从南边过来了
Thumb-thumbs and Fooglies coming up the south hall.
有办法吗？
Got an idea?
有了
Yeah.
唐纳根干员？
Agent Donnagon?
我爸妈呢？
Where's my mom and dad?
谢谢
Thanks.
- 录好了 - 他说什么？
- I got it. - What'd he say?
倒过来听
I'll play it backwards.
"他们在地牢 快"
They're in the dungeon. Hurry.
问他们第三脑在哪？
See if they know where the Brain room is.
到处都是大姆哥
Thumb-thumbs...everywhere.
看他们爱不爱泡泡
Let's see if they like bubbles.
待会再来救你们
We'll be back for you,fellow agents.
谢了
Sknaht!
所有机器人请到
All robots please report...
4 5 6号舱 准备进行装置
to docking bays four,five,and six for immediate loading.
这个是通风口
This is the ventilator shaft here.
对 地牢在另一边
But the dungeon's on the other side of the castle.
怎样能不被侦测到？
How do we get there undetected?
他们比上次聪明了
I think they've gotten smarter since the last time we met.
有侵入者
Intruder.
- 你行吗？- 应该可以
- Can you make it? - I think so.
快
Come on. Come on !
- 卡门 - 去找爸妈
- Carmen ! - Find Mom and Dad !
(虚拟实境房)
希望这里可以到关爸妈的地牢
I hope this leads to the dungeon.
喂 小子
You there.
你手上是什么？
What's that on your hands?
是疹子 对嘛？
Warts,aren't they?
这下好了
Oh,great.
手出汗就会长疹子
From sweaty hands sprout warts.
为什么手会出汗？
Do you know why you have sweaty hands?
因为常常害怕
From being scared all the time.
我不觉得你害怕
You don't look very scared to me.
因为我很生气 你抓走我爸妈
That's because I'm mad. You kidnapped my parents...
制造机器坏小孩 还吞了我姐
made psycho robot children,and swallowed up my sister.
那不是我计划的
But I didn't want any of that.
- 我以为暗黑破坏王是天才 - 真的？
- I thought Floop was a genius. - You did?
你有看我的节目
You watch my show?
你才知道
More than you know.
迷你安
Alexander Minion.
克兹干员
Agent Cortez.
真高兴再见面
Wonderful to see you again.
- 你认识他？- 对
- You know him? - Yeah.
他参与第三脑计划
He was on the Third Brain Project...
他被我发现 他想把自己的想法放进系统
until I noticed he was trying to inject his own ideas into the system.
我举发他
I turned him in.
他就被赶出欧斯
He was thrown out of the OSS.
我虽不像破坏王那么天才
I'm afraid I'm not nearly the artist Floop is.
但别担心
But not to worry.
我想到一个不错的主意
I have something else in mind.
你这样有什么好处？
What do you think you're going to accomplish by doing this?
克兹太太
Well,you see,Mrs. Cortez...
我一直是个有逻辑 目标确立
I've always been methodical,goal oriented.
神经质的人
Psychotically so.
我不怕你 迷你安
I'm not afraid of you,Alex.
我想每个人
So I think it's refreshing...
都应该偶尔做点
to every once in a while...
好玩的事
have some fun.
别担心你的小孩
Oh,and don't worry about your little brats.
他们每天早上七点半到八点
They'll still be able to see you.
都能在电视上看到你
Every weekday morning between 7:30 and 8:00.
暗黑破坏王大功告成了吧
I trust this time Floop will have a success to show us.
伟大的破坏王去外地洽公
The Fabulous Floop is away on other business,sir.
军团已完成了
Your army is complete.
终极战士正等候指挥
The ultimate destructive force is now within your grasp.
等我看到 我才能相信
I'll believe that when I see it.
欢迎归队 葛小姐
Welcome back,Ms. Gradenko.
回来真好 迷你安
It's good to be back,Alex.
永远不要生小孩
Let's never have children.
- 迷你安才是幕后恶魔 - 对
- So Minion is the evil one. - Yes.
对 但我也有错
But I will be blamed.
你绝对有理由怪罪我
You have every reason to be disappointed in me.
关掉它后 你会做什么？
So what would you do if you could shut this thing off and get out of here?
不可能 只能从外面关
It's impossible. It can only be turned off from the outside.
假设嘛
Just suppose.
我会去阻止迷你安
I'd stop Minion.
阻止机器娃娃军团
I'd stop the robot army and hope...
好让世界原谅我
that the world would forgive me.
暗黑破坏王 你是我的英雄
You're my hero,Floop...
我帮你 你也要帮我
so I'm gonna help you,then you're gonna help me.
- 一定要阻止迷你安 - 还有一件事
- Minion must be stopped. - Just one thing.
我的节目 还需要什么？
My show...what does it need?
我知道它很需要一个东西
I know it needs something desperately...
但想不出来
but I can't figure it out.
也许你想得到
Maybe you can?
需要小孩
It needs children.
抓稳了
Hold still.
我们去阻止迷你安
Now let's stop Minion.
要阻止他 一定要阻止
Must be stopped. Must be stopped !
这一拳为姐姐报仇
This one's for my sister!
朱尼
Oh,Juni.
哈罗
Hola.
卡门 朱尼
Carmen? Juni?
- 妈 - 妈妈
- Mom ! - Mom ! Aah !
那是我的怪脸
That's my Fooglie!
我画的那个
The one I drew.
是爸爸
It's dad.
你们终于来了
You're here!
- 他来干嘛？- 他来帮忙的
- What's he doing here? - He's OK. He's OK.
你们怎么来的？
How did you get here?
(酸性蜡笔)
妈 我常常跷课到处玩
Mom,I've been skipping school,going places...
到城里坐摩天轮
taking ferry rides in the city...
没关系 我知道
It's OK. It's OK. I know.
回家再说
We'll talk about it when we get home.
- 跑到贝立斯… - 什么？去哪？
- Running off to Belize. - What? You went where?
你说的对 回家再说
You're right. Let's just talk about this when we get home.
不 不 不
No,no,no,no.
把心里话告诉我吧？
You can tell me everything now,OK?
你是想离开家人？
Is that where you want to be,free from your family?
以前想 现在不想了
I used to. Not anymore.
你把我爸变成怪脸？
You turned my dad into a Fooglie?
不是我
No,I didn't.
但我可以把他变回来
But I might be able to change him back.
各位
Gentlemen...
你们的军团 正要前来接受检阅
your army marches to meet us as we speak.
感谢你们的信心及耐心
Your faith and your patience have meant more than you know.
我谨代表暗黑破坏王
I speak for Mr. Floop when I say that the value...
祝福我们绵长的友谊…
we place on partnership is...
迷你安 我是暗黑破坏王
Minion! This is Floop.
立刻到研究室来
Please report to the robotics lab at once.
机器人出了很大的问题
We have huge,major,big-time problems with the robots.
暗黑破坏王不是不在吗？
I thought you said Floop wasn't here.
他是不在
He's not.
迷你安 出了大麻烦 大问题
A problem,Mr. Minion,as in mucho grande problemo.
我去看一下
I'm gonna just be a moment.
迷你安
Minion!
暗黑破坏王
Floop?
你在哪？
Where are you?
在你后面
Behind you.
你以为你在干什么？
What do you think you're doing?
你应该跟其他人一样排队
You're supposed to be in line with the others.
你怎么不去排队？
You're supposed to be with the others.
- 别学我 - 别学我
- Stop that. - Stop that!
- 别胡闹 - 别胡闹
- Stop that this instant! - Stop that this instant!
立刻闭嘴
Stop that right now!
不然呢？
Or what?
真聪明的孩子 老克兹
Clever boy you've got there,Cortez. Very clever indeed.
他遗传他妈妈的
Yes. He gets that from his mother.
我把女儿还你 我们停战如何？
Can I offer some sort of truce in exchange for your daughter?
你爱说笑
Spoken for.
我没看见你 我没看见她
There you are. Didn't see you. Didn't see her.
让你也尝一下
I am going to show you what happens...
害我家人的下场
when you cross the line and involve family.
舒舒服服躺好
Now let's get nice and comfortable.
太美了
Yes.
谢谢
Promising. Thank you.
- 你不可以 - 对 那你自己来
- You couldn't possibly. - No,but you can.
按紧一点 英格丽
Don't let go,Ingrid.
你们两个来
Hey,you two,come on.
白痴
Fools.
快来
Come on.
不能让军团离开城堡
We have to keep the army from leaving the castle.
唯一办法是去控制室
Our only chance is to get to the control room...
看任务设定好了没
and hope that their missions have not been programmed.
万一设定好了？
And what if they have?
那就谁也挡不住了
Then there's no one on earth who can stop them.
- 一个个进去 - 走吧
- One at a time. - Go. Go.
左边
Left,left,left,left!
走那边 爸妈呢？
That way. Where's Mom and Dad?
被机器人抓了
Your doppelgangers have them.
能从这关掉吗？
Can you shut them down from here?
太迟了
It's too late.
所有的机器人都装了第三脑
The Third Brain is linked not only to them...
但所有的机器人儿童
but to all the robot children.
- 不能移除吗？- 有五百个 怎么移除？
- Can't you remove it? - We can't take 500 brains out!
- 那就重新设定 - 要好几周
- So don't. Just reprogram it. - That would take weeks!
- 只要改两个字 - 对了 二元转换
- Just two words. - A binary switch. Of course.
他们就会把"好"变成"坏"
So they would define right as wrong...
"坏"变成"好" 走
And wrong as right. Come on.
但没那么容易
But it's not that simple.
想办法 待会见
Figure it out. We'll be back for you.
教他们变好人
Teach them to be good.
请坐"倪"先生 会舒服点
Have a seat,Mr. Lithp. You'll be more comfortable.
我姓"李"
It's Lisp.
葛小姐 我要看见我的军团才会舒服
My army,Ms. Gradenko,is the only comfort I need.
马上就来了
They're on their way now,sir.
迷你安？
Minion?
你头怎么了？
What happened to your head?
别担心 可以再变回来的
Oh,don't worry. I think it's reversible.
妈 爸
Mom ! Dad !
小心
Careful.
他们现在更强更聪明了
They're stronger and smarter now.
我们也是
So are we.
看吧？
See?
雪特…冰淇淋
Oh,shi...take mushrooms.
我们走
Let's go.
老李 原来是你在主使
Lisp. Should have known you were behind this.
这位是迷你安吧
I take it you are Minion.
这位是葛小姐
Ms. Gradenko...I think.
是我没错
Oh,it's me,all right.
你孩子给我的新造型
I owe my new look to your children.
该给他们奖励金
Remind me to raise their allowance.
现在该展示一下
Minion,I think now would be a good time...
你们制造的超级小孩了
to see a demonstration of your wonderfully demonic children.
没问题
Certainly.
制伏你爸妈真容易
Your parents were so easy to capture...
你也好不到哪去
and you're not any better.
可怜的小朱尼
Poor little Juni.
虚弱 又没力
Defenseless and weak.
没用的小废物
You're a worthless little squirt.
别听她的 你不是废物
Juni! Don't listen to her. You're not worthless!
是你找到这个地方
You figured out how to get us here.
你让破坏王知道他是好人
You helped Floop realize he was good,not bad.
你让怪脸说出爸妈在地牢
You talked to the Fooglies and saved Mom and Dad.
你很强 朱尼 你很强壮
You're strong,Juni! You're strong!
但没那么强壮啦
You're not that strong,Juni!
吃奶的小朱尼
Puny...Juni.
一切都结束了
It's all over.
瞬间接著剂
Instant cement!
应该可以撑一下
That should hold them.
- 快去找爸妈 - 好主意
- Let's go find Mom and Dad. - Good idea.
所有机器人向大房间
All robots report to the grand room...
做最具破坏力的最后展示
for a final demonstration of your destructive powers.
- 妈 爸 - 朱尼
- Mom,Dad ! - Juni!
闭上眼 别看他们
Carmen,Juni,close your eyes.
我们不想让你看
We don't want you to see this,OK?
有办法吗？
Any ideas?
我在想
I'm thinking. I'm thinking.
太好了 太好了
Wonderful. Wonderful.
- 卡门？- 朱尼？
- Carmen? - No. Juni?
我们是一家人 一家人
I've thought it out. Yes. I've thought it out.
我大概想到了
I think I got it.
说啊
Tell us.
家人们 这么做
Family,here's what we do.
我负责右边一百
I'll take the hundred on the right.
你负责左边一百
Ingrid,you take the hundred on the left.
卡门 中间左边一百
Carmen,hundred center-left.
朱尼 中间右边一百
Juni,center-right.
一定可以
It'll work. It'll work.
爸 一共有五百个
That's 500 total,Dad.
我们还需要一个人
We need one more person.
- 红贝 - 哈罗 小弟
- Isador. - Hello,little brother.
孩子们
Children !
把他们骨头拆了
Tear them limb from limb.
怎么教他们？
Good. How? How?
让环境引导他们
I'll have to teach them. Shaped by environment,man...
对啊
Of course!
迷你安 叫他们放开我
Minion ! Tell them to put me down !
他们有自己意志了
Their mind is a mirror now,sir.
我们说的话他们左边进 右边出
Anything we tell them goes in one ear and out the other!
你干嘛回来？
Why did you come back?
跟我离开理由一样
For the same reason I left.
你知道吗？
You know what?
我忘了那个理由
I don't remember that reason.
我也是
Neither do I.
没事了
It's OK,it's OK.
没事 哭吧
It's OK. Let it go. Let it go.
他没事了
He's fine. He's gonna be fine.
他感情丰富 拉丁人
He's emotional. Latinos.
没事了 好了
OK. That's it.That's it. That's it.
你教他们什么？
So,what did you teach them?
我没教他们什么
It's not what I can teach the children...
是你教了我
but what you taught me.
今天你赢了 不是因为
You won today,Juni,and not because...
你最强壮
you were the biggest or the strongest...
是因为你有纯真的心和想法
but because you were pure of heart and of mind.
机器人也学到了这个
And now the robots have learned that as well.
谢谢你
Thank you.
我们如愿以偿再次出任务
We went on the old-fashioned adventure I always wanted.
却没做对一件事
And we didn't do one thing right.
对
Nope.
至少我们做对"这两个"
We did two things right.
告诉你们一件事
There is something that we have to tell you.
你爸爸和我
Your father and I...
是间谍
we're secret agents.
告诉你们一件事
We have something to tell you.
我们也是间谍
We're secret agents,too.
世界各国陆续传出佳讯
Eight more incidents witnessed today all in different countries...
又一群小孩有惊人善举
of yet another group of children who've done some incredible good deeds.
这些神奇的孩子
It seems that a day doesn't go by that another amazing child...
不断进行服务和慈善工作
performs some outstanding act of charity or community service.
他们是谁？
Who are these children...
为什么这么爱行善？
and why are they so good at being good?
我要看财经版
I gotta have the business section.
你不是"退休"了？
I thought you closed down your shop.
还是要注意市场动态
Yeah,but I gotta keep tabs on free enterprise.
两位 别再吵了行吗？
Boys,can we please stop fighting?
小朋友们 快来看
Hey,kids,it's time for...
暗黑破坏秀
Floop's Fooglies!
早安 孩子们
Good morning,my children.
今天我要介绍
Today,I'd like to introduce you...
两个新角色 到我们节目里
to two new characters on our show...
卡门妮塔和朱尼多
Carmenita and Junito.
克兹先生
Ah,Cortezes.
远东发生一件紧急任务
An emergency assignment has come up in the Far East.
需要立刻出动
I need you on it right away.
抱歉 老戴
Oh,sorry,Devlin.
还没跟家人商量
We haven't talked about this as a family yet,so...
是否要退休
Whether we come out of retirement...
我们要和孩子们一起决定
or not is a decision that is up to us and our kids.
格瑞利 英格丽 不是找你们
Uh,Gregorio,Ingrid,I wasn't talking to you.
这任务需要卡门和朱尼
No,this assignment is for Carmen and Juni.
我们需要他们
They're the ones we need.
他们是有史以来最佳的干员
They're the two most amazing field agents that this organization's ever seen.
孩子们 怎么样？
So what do you say,kids?
接受任务吗？
You up for it?
要克兹家人出马
Devlin,if you want the Cortezes...
就要全体出动
you take all the Cortezes...
爸妈也要去
even Mom and Dad.
从今以后我们一起行动
From now on,whatever we do,we do together.
做间谍 很简单
Spy work...that's easy.
一家人团结
Keeping a family together...
很难
that's difficult.
是最值得努力的任务
And that's the mission worth fighting for.